yeah back then I really thought it was
like a it
was the kind of job that only genius
level sort of people couldn't work and
then you met me and yeah basically and
then how you you knew ah if this dumbass
can do it then you know I can do it too
yeah
[Music]
that's
all righty sup y'all this time around uh
I'm sitting down with two of my best
friends so sakaguchi and Quai Kono we're
going to talk about the mentorship
experience in bug Bounty and we're going
to talk about not only the ins and outs
of how to do mentorship and uh you know
facts about how to do it but we're also
going to talk about the messy thing that
is learning about Bounty what kind of
difficulties come up what kind of ways
mentors can be
counterproductive and uh what kind of
lessons we've learned along the way in
building you know sort of the mentor
mentee relationship uh hope you enjoy
this episode I will also add in this
segment um we forgot to do the
giveaway uh and we we were supposed to
do it two weeks ago and then we didn't
and we got caught up with live hacking
event stuff so congrats to n chickens on
Twitter for winning the uh J hadex the
bug bounty hunting methodology uh
giveaway it's going to be an awesome
course I'm super excited for you um for
those of you that uh didn't win my
condolences but you can still get a seat
uh by hitting the description hitting
the link in the description down below
to go to jx's website and sign up there
it's probably the best $550 you'll ever
spend so with that hope you enjoy the
episode all right you guys see this it
is we have started the recording this
time we just we just got like you know
five minutes into the episode we we went
through our a little pre pre-episode
warm-up pre-episode Shake uh and then we
realized we are not recording the audio
at all just the video so sorry about
that a little bit of a false start um
but thanks for coming on uh just for the
audience these two guys these two lovely
gentlemen right here
are some of my best friends from the
time that I was living in Japan um and
yeah man just so many so many good
memories with you guys um in Japan and
uh during you know being the bug Bounty
evangelist that I am I uh you know had a
conversation with these guys about bug
Bounty and both of them have expressed
interest so has already gotten a a job
in the field um as he'll tell you in
just a moment but both of them have uh
sort of expressed a desire to work in uh
cyber security in general specifically
offensive cyber security and or bug
Bounty uh as a career path so um we
started to do some mentorship some
training and that sort of things and
that's kind of what I was thinking about
uh thinking we would talk about today is
like what is a good blueprint what is a
good um a good pathway for a beginner to
take coming into bug Bounty and and for
people the more advanced listeners that
are that are here um which is most of
our audience if you have someone that
you're working with that you want to
help grow in bug Bounty how can you
effectively do that so hopefully these
two have brought some good constructive
criticism for me today we'll see if uh
if they're able to put aside their uh
Japanese uh Tendencies about saying oh
everything's great everything's great
you know we'll see and uh and and give
me some actual constructive criticism
but um before we jump into that let's um
I'll we'll go ahead and do a an
interview and since uh an intro and
since on the Fall start we had so start
his intro we're gonna have Kodi start
his intro this time just to keep you on
your
toes all I mean first of all thank you
so much for having us on this podcast
I'm really happy to talk to you on this
and uh my name is Kodi um I also go by
the name of Kodi trai which is my heck
handle and uh I'm currently not really
working yeah uh but I'm in search of
New Opportunities yeah I'm in the
process of actually applying for a
couple of Japanese cyber secur companies
and you've already graduated right yeah
yeah uh I guess it's about it yeah yeah
yeah so anybody who's in the Japan cyber
security space hit Codi up if you've got
any hit me up any any opportunities and
uh well I guess maybe we'll circle
around to that again after you've
listened to Kodi talk in this podcast
about his experiences and what kind of
stuff we've worked on together and the
bani realm um all right so you're up
next so my name is so and my hacka one
account is
Moko and I started bbon and cyber
security staff from three years ago
thanks to Justin also now I'm working as
a fulltime uh security engineer at GMO
uh Japanese company would you say would
you say that it's a security engineer
position it's it's pretty much entirely
offensive security right yeah it's like
a web application tester web application
test yeah also doing a bit of like U
bani as a hobby like trying to find some
CVS and stuff nice that's also another
hobby very cool man very cool um so I
guess let's since so's already got the
mic uh when did you start getting
interested in bug bounties and give us a
little background education background
and then how you switched sort
of skirt CH change change change paths
into bug Bounty I think that was uh that
was exactly three years ago right three
years ago October yeah pretty much mon
this day right yeah this season so I was
a I was a senior of of University in
Japan and my major was French Regional
studies so I was studying French and
also do some like what uh what what
university was that in Japan that Tokyo
University Tokyo University uh top
university in Japan uh so
let's just put that out the Harvard of
Japan of sorts let's let's put that out
there all right continue yeah so I
wanted to be like I I didn't have like a
specific dreams but uh that time I kind
of want to be a diplomat because I
thought it's cool also I was studying
English and French so I thought it would
be a great fit for me right so that was
like three years ago and then I met
Justin at a like a Bible study of of my
church in Yokohama and started to hang
out with him and so one day we went on a
trip together and there like he kind of
introduced me uh about like what he does
also like his job and bani and stuff and
I got interested and that's how got how
I got started Yeah man so I just I think
that experience is a little bit kind of
crazy to me looking back on it because I
remember the time the conversation so
and I had when he you know and at this
point you had no it experience at all
yeah Zer not even really using the
computer for anything besides just
school work right yeah yeah um and so
you know to for him to be like yeah you
know what actually I'm really interested
in that I would like to learn how to do
that my my first reaction is like of
course you know this guy is smart
because he's at this University and
because I've had conversations with him
but the chances of you actually doing
that were very slim in my opinion in my
experience right and so when you said
that I was like okay
um I'm gonna give you some reading
material okay yeah and and I gave you
some reading material and what was
something amazing happened which was
that the next time I talked to you you
had read it
all right which which doesn't sound that
crazy but it but it really is you had
read it all and um and you not only had
you done that but I remember you came
back to me and you said hey so at this
one point in this one piece of material
it references application Json and I
didn't know what that
was
yeah and and so I was looking that up
and then like you know you had some
question about Json structure so it
showed that you went another layer
deeper in the learning material as well
um which really made it made an impact
on me and really impressed me with that
so um you know that's that's why we kind
of moved forward with the with the bug
Bounty I think piece for you um or at
least with the more active Hands-On
mentorship because that was a that was a
really impressive uh moment moment for
for me and so diving into that first I
don't know how clear of a memory you
have of this but diving into that first
material how was that I mean do do you
remember being particularly lost or how
did you how did you take that first step
because the first step is a big one so
so first of first of all I I think one
thing I really remember is like because
Justin told me that he's a doing back
Bounty and seems like you know he's good
at it so I checked hack website and I
saw him ranking at like 11th or like
12th at like annual ranking yeah and
that was like probably one of the most
like like like the biggest things to me
and as like if you know if you're good
at something that's good if you're good
at like if you ranks at like 11th in the
world that's impressive like not just
impressive that's like a pretty good
super good and if your friend ranks 11th
in the world at something then you got
to learn that right you got to at least
know like the basics that's a very weird
way of thinking about like like yeah
that's such a precious opportunity there
are like only 11 people right at the
same level so that's how I got
interested and for the material that you
gave me that's like really hard because
like I like you said I I didn't know
what Json is I didn't know what PHP is
like I really have no idea what like any
concept of anything in the books war was
so that was really hard but also I was
like this looks pretty like interesting
because I know nothing about this you
know and so you know every time you came
across something new it's just starting
sort of a recursive process of like now
I go read about that right and then you
know you dive deeper on that um and I
think the fact that you're able to do
that is is really really impressive and
is probably one of the key indicators of
your success to this point um but we'll
come back to that CI um so I guess the
question that I wanted to ask you is a
little bit different than the question
that I wanted to ask so for this one um
so so and I had already started sort of
doing some hacking stuff when you I
guess got more interested in it but I
also feel like there was some sort of
prein or at least pre time when you
expressed interest to me that you that
you wanted to be you know get into
hacking what what kind of um what kind
of
experiences did you have prior what kind
of stuff did you look up what kind of
image image of hacking did you have
prior to saying hey Justin I'd like to
learn more about B
Bounty wow that's a really good question
I think yeah I think it goes all the way
back to when I was 13 or 14 that's when
I was first introduced to the world of
hacking technically yeah I basically
watched this documentary is Thing by a
Japanese TV program it was was about
this American hacker guy uh named Max
Butler I think yeah also known as Iceman
and he was
basically working for FBI but
surreptitiously doing some black hat
hacking oh really steing so
many yeah so that in a way yeah to be
perfectly honest really fascinated me it
wasn't like hey I want to steal CR
numbers in as well no but I was just you
know I think it was the the capability
he had you know over the world of the
internet yeah yeah cuz it was
physically basically just him and his
laptop right right so I was like holy
[__] like yeah can really one person do
that it it definitely appeals to you
know the the more individualistic type
you know you know because it like you
said it is you and your laptop against
all the defenses or the world you know
at that point so yeah so that was super
nuts and but at that time I never really
looked at it as a realistic career path
that I might be able to take because
yeah back then I really thought it was
like a it
was the kind of job that only genius
level sort of people couldn't work and
then you met me basically and then how
you you knew ah if this D mask can do it
then you know I can do it too yeah
that's no no no no no just kidding but
but you really made me you know you
really sort of proved that you can you
know work that as a job yeah you know as
an ethical hacker right and if you reach
a certain level I mean it could be very
very high but once you reach it then you
might be able to leave nomadically which
was you know something I was always sort
of dreaming of doing yeah I I remember
talking us talking about this that was
that was one of the the end goals for
you in general was to be able to I guess
work remotely and even further knee
further so sort
of man my my Japanese is is getting in
the way because whenever I have a
conversation with these guys I I we
switch out of in and out of Japanese and
and in English so so it gets in the way
but we'll try to keep it English for
this so furthermore you know if you're
able to do that on your own schedule
right on your own timeline that's a big
plus for you um and I think yeah I
remember I remember you mentioning that
in the beginning so that's that's one of
the main I guess motivators for you too
right yeah yeah that's that's that's
definitely that's definitely a big you
know that was one of the that's the
thing that brought me to Japan in the
first place was the fact that I could
work remotely and working on my own own
time schedule that was really that was
really big um Kodi uh so then you know
we started talking a little bit you
started seeing me and so start working
on stuff yeah and it starts to sort of
materialize in your brain hey this is a
this is a a route that you you could go
um I guess I think I know so's answer to
this already because so just straight
from the beginning so was like okay wait
I've never even heard of this okay teach
me you know so there wasn't any sort of
pre-research before you and me sort of
establishing a a Mente Mentor
relationship you know but for you Kodi
was there any research you did into
hacking or like that before you got
started uh kind of yeah I also did the
you know uh one of the things that so it
just you know looking up your name one
and because I you know before I met you
I basically heard that you know from one
of her uh neutral friends that you're
basically one of the best hackers out
there I was like okay okay sure yeah
sure and then I you know looked it up
and wow but I was it was still it seemed
really unrealistic to me you know
because I didn't I wasn't really
familiar with cyber security or anything
or it in general right but I think yeah
in that sense so really showed me that
without having
any you know uh yeah he was a French
major yeah yeah just it or you know
programming experiences you could
actually start it so yeah I think after
watching
him doing some hack and you know doing
some mentorship with you I yeah finally
made a decision to you know do the same
thing look look my my guys my guys I
love it and and you know so and I have
have had you know so many good hacking
experiences together already as well and
and CI we've had a handful as well um
and so it's so great to be able to do
this job with you guys you know you know
even even as the uh you know as the Gap
begins to close a little bit in
knowledge and and so starts teaching me
stuff about stuff things that I don't
know and and uh and you know as you
continue to grow there as well CL I I
think it'll be even more fun um so it's
happened so it's well you know here's
the other thing man I think as as a
mentor you when you're having to
re-explain stuff as well you start to
question right like for example the time
I tried to you know do a SE Surf and I
deleted your I deleted his like goto
music account via se- surf cuz it had
right premium account uh and I learned
some stuff about uh Sam site strict
cookies that day right um so as we
continue to grow together not not just
you know you guys growing but I grow as
well so that's really cool um the next
question that I had and I guess I should
probably pick one of you to answer this
yeah let's let's hear from so um
so can you think of any time where you
sort of had like a aha moment that where
you you really started to understand
some piece of of hacking or has it just
been really really
gradual I'd say it's been always really
really gradual and always like Looking
Backward I I'm like oh I've made a bit
of progress right you know over the last
few month or over the last year
something like that yeah so so probably
not any any like you know all of a
sudden the lights come on and can see
moment on any of that stuff yeah I I I
suspected that that would be the case um
for you so I mean I guess we started off
I guess working in in the same way that
I we started working with with Codi
which is act control uh vulnerabilities
and xss and and idors and stuff like
that um do you think that's the same
route you would take now and do you
think that you would change any of that
that at all um or or do you think that
that is the correct path to get you to
where to where you're at you can think
about that for a second if you need to
yeah I guess if someone starts from
where I was which is like absolutely
zero Basics like zero knowledge on cyber
security or like even like computer
science as a whole I think that was a
correct route
because like now it's like one of the
you know one of the easy ones right but
like 3 years ago I could barely
understand like what Access Control bags
are and how I can exploit that like the
same for idor I mean of course if you go
further with like a bishop Fox Jason
search and stuff they're more complex
outoor things but like easy parts of
idor and access controls is I think
comparatively easier to understand for
like beginners like me three years ago
so I think it was a good route yeah I I
I kind of wish we had recorded this
podcast a little bit closer to our it's
been about what it's almost it's been
about two years maybe a year if we count
some of the time you were in America um
since we really did some hardcore
Hands-On mentorship right so I'm sure
I'm sure some of that has faded a little
bit now um you know the the the the
techniques and and the way that I I sort
of taught some bug Bounty stuff but the
way the way if I recall correctly that
we approached this was you know we we
first explained
um what happens when you put a URL in a
browser right and and hopefully you know
at that time you know we we I we drilled
that pretty often we did that a lot
right um and and I think that's you know
once you have that sort of foundation in
place then then you can start moving on
to those those sort of vulnerabilities
do you think you had CU we we probably
went over that part of it 10 15 times
right what happens from from all right
user puts the URL in the browser you
know it converts the domain name into it
pares the URL pulls out the domain name
converts the name domain name into an IP
via DNS and then it instanes the TCP
connection you know we went through all
of that probably 10 15 times do you
think that having that basis allowed you
to grip something like idor and access
control bugs a little bit a little bit
easier or do you think it would have
been better just be like hey here's an
HTTP request this HTTP
request you know controls how the
computer talks to the server rotate the
ID see see the vulnerability I mean what
do you think do you think that's too
[Music]
deep he just said he he just said in
Japanese Ah that's a tricky one uh I'm
going to think about that for a second
so
yeah I guess for one I I wouldn't say
I've mastered like TCP stuff right right
and
like yeah still I I see we learn all
these things and sometimes when I have
to learn some like hp2 things like you
know I just always realize that I don't
understand absolutely like anything
right right everyone has that
moment um I think basic was necessary
and also like at the end of the day you
have to learn that right so I think
learning just
Basics
ah I don't know if it's related I don't
know if it's related okay okay all right
no no no I like I like this take this is
I don't know if you guys know this
English vocabulary word but hot take
have you you guys kodine knows that so
doesn't know it uh hot take is like a an
opinion uh that is different than
you know one might expect or what
popular culture believes right so this
this is a hot it might be a little bit
of a hot take here so so tell me about
why you're changing your mind a little
bit on
this so one uh so so the one of the
reasons I was learning cyber secur and
hacking from you three years ago was
like I said because you're like one of
the top hackers in the world so I like
didn't really matter how fast I can grow
like how much money I can get it was
just like a pure Hobby and I just wanted
to understand at least basics of what
you do so that's why you know try trying
to understand DNS stuff DCP stuff all
these things matter to me so for me
personally it was necessary and I really
enjoyed that but at the same time I
don't I'm not super sure if that helped
me understand access control thing Ador
things like business logic things better
at that time that I'm not sure about so
so you guys both listen to the podcast
you know that we like to debate here a
little bit we like to do some we like to
do some critical thinking right like I
like to debate so I'm gonna I'm gonna
you know I'm gonna place in Devil's
Advocate I'm gonna take you know the
other side for a little bit but first I
want to hear kodi's kodi's opinion so
Kodi same sort of
question is it important to know that
piece that I talked about when you put
the URL in the browser what happens
before you start learning things like
idor and access control
vulnerabilities yeah that definitely was
necessary for me yeah and yeah in that
sense that was a really good start um
because I feel like that was the
really at least to me the bare minimum
that I really needed to
actually go uh look for some bugs I mean
in this case only idors but yeah yeah so
and obviously I didn't really you know
at that time when I when you just you
know explained how yeah just starting
from you
know just missing with the with the URL
um URL bar and just how briefly like all
the HP messages you know work um I
didn't have a comprehensive understand
understanding of you know how ID Wars
could actually happen and stuff but
right it's sort of foundational
knowledge but I could still you know as
a matter of fact go find some bugs I
mean obviously with your help but yeah
so yeah that worked pretty well for me
yeah yeah and I think I think that makes
sense too but so so all right so let's
let's let's give it back to so here and
let's let's have a little little chat
about this okay so on one hand I do
agree I do agree that um you know it
would be possible to to search otherwise
but I think for me and it sounds like
like maybe the cas is for kod as well
it's kind of hard for us to visualize
what's happening until we understand
what's happening at a little bit of a
lower level right because like if I say
to
you I mean I guess you could understand
at the level like we put a we put these
htttp requests in a box you know in this
box inside a burp Suite right and we we
change the number and we press send uh
and then that just communicates to the
server I guess we could do it at that
level but do you think it would be hard
for you to grip conceptually what's
happening without that explanation or do
you think really gripping what happening
conceptually but uh you know comes even
later after the URL explanation what
what what do you think about that like
do you have to understand what's
happening on the back end for you to
really see the full
picture so I guess um I kind of agree
with uh kodai like you know way he put
it right I I'd say you know I kind of
start to get persuaded right but what I
my point was
like yeah at that level it's related you
know but it's not directly related so
well it's a little bit early on too you
know in your in your in your experience
to really have to take in a bunch of
technical information like rfc's you
know reading HTTP RFC talking about you
know TCP level connections which we'll
never use ever again so really it's
mostly the HTTP layer right that we need
to be understanding do you
agree
I mean like at the end of the day like I
really kind of this argument really
makes uh me remember the argument of you
know hack the hacker the hackers need to
like
program yeah and like I think answers
from most hackers are like not
absolutely necessary but absolutely
helpful yeah so you think this is
similar yeah this is I feel like this is
similar like it's thing super helpful to
understand
idor but is it like absolutely necessary
then I don't think it it is yeah yeah
that makes sense I think I think uh I
think that's a really good parallel you
know drawing drawing those parallels in
between because you can you can kind of
see like like you said you really could
find it's simple enough where you really
could if you understood the concept of
idor this concept of an ID and this
concept of trusting the ID from the
client side right you could really find
vulnerabilities without having to learn
that uh but really it does help and I
think that's that's a strong parallel to
programming that's good okay
so let's talk about mentorship a little
bit let's talk about the times when us
three are sitting in a room hands on the
keyboard
okay your boy your boy Justin's a little
quirky sometimes right so uh I have a
little bit of an eccentric style or a
little uh bit of an odd style of
teaching bug Bounty um what what are
some things that worked for you and some
things that didn't work for you with the
teaching teaching style I and once again
I know this is a couple years back but
um you know I I often for example to
give you an example had you teach things
back to
me what what do you think about that in
other teaching styles so first since you
got the
or if you need to think we can give it
to Kodi too all right we well so it's
taking a little I I I caught so after a
work day here brain's taking a second
all right uh kite what do you what do
you think about that um yeah
so yeah your style of mentorship you
know having us uh okay okay wait wait
wait before you get I can see before I
we get into
this this is not supposed to be a Justin
your amazing bloody BL sort of session
okay so please try to keep that to a Min
a minimal okay this is this is supposed
to be talk to me about the efficacy of
the technique okay okay so this is gonna
be my genuine opinion and uh yeah the
thing that you just touched on you know
um you having us uh explain what you
just explained to us that really yeah
that's actually one of
the greatest things you did for us I
guess yeah it was could be very
challenging but definitely to understand
how
um almost anything I guess you need to
you got to be able to you know have the
capability to
reproduce what you just did you know
explain what you just learned so yeah
that's definitely one thing I really
liked about your uh style do you think
it was it was too
stressful I feel like I be lying if I
said not at all
but but uh you know that's the I really
needed that stress you know for my brain
and that
definitely yeah pushed me
to um you know spot what I didn't really
understand precisely yeah just
troubleshooting issues properly yeah so
have you have you thought about so this
this is a common technique
it's it's probably interesting because
you know I'm making you guys do this but
really what I'm doing the technique that
I'm sort of mimicking it goes way back
further um and back into you know
history uh sort of rooted in the
Socratic method um with Socrates a
philosopher uh but uh more commonly it's
used in it uh a little bit a little bit
different but related topic called the
rubber ducky method have you guys heard
of that no rubber duck yeah yeah yeah
okay so has um so essentially the way
that you can reproduce this for
yourselves as well is May force yourself
to explain stuff to inanimate objects so
a lot of programmers they'll have a
rubber duck and you know yellow rubber
duck sitting on their on their on their
desk right and they'll uh they'll
explain things to that duck to try to
help
them figure out where the flaws in their
logic are right and I have that with a
little stuffed animal Pokemon Dratini on
my desk I don't know because the Pokemon
names are different in Japanese I don't
know if you know Dratini but he's kind
of like a like a lizard snaky boy uh
evolves into big dragon um uh but yeah
so that's that's a that's technique have
you guys used that at all in in your
life before or is this something that I
should have equipped you with years ago
that might have helped that's I've
definitely used that yeah um even when I
try to just practice my you know
pronunciation in English and stuff oh
yeah yeah I try to like yeah it's
basically about talking to some
something imaginary right right yeah um
yeah I do that too Dall the air um yeah
and I definitely you know did the same
thing uh in cyber security yeah yeah
what what about you so do you have uh do
you got any stuffed animals you talk to
I mean I do that always with my friends
oh really you know I mean like
accidentally right right right like when
I was a high school student I always now
you all know what kind of guy so is like
hey man you know you let me tell you
about this new Json article I read you
know like and like yeah when I was a
high schooler I did it to my sister like
there like complex math problems I
cannot solve right and I you know bring
it to my sister because my sister's
pretty smart right and then I'm like
like and then like halfway through I'm
like ah I know sorry I know I know how
to do it you know and these days I do
with my hacker friends you know like
reala for example I can send a message
on Discord I'm like what what what this
is I don't understand and halfway
through I'm like sorry I I understand
it's great when you've got friends on
other time zones for that too because
they won't they won't respond right away
and then you they'll just wake up to a
barrage of messages like oh dude this is
the weirdest thing I can't figure this
out what's going on here's what's
happening I got it actually you know so
that's good um so do you think I mean do
do any other um so essentially the goal
of this this sort of portion of the
podcast is to try to equip the listeners
with techniques that they can use to
help other people their mentees grow or
mentees themselves how they can grow so
do you have any other things that come
to mind from your experience um you know
working as a mentee or collaborating on
y''s bug Bounty growth together that uh
that come to mind any techniques or
thoughts so for me I think like like all
like
these like teaching styles or even like
tips that you gave me really helped me
for sure but at the end of the day I
feel like it's about me right if I want
to improve myself I have to work hard so
I think um what I learned from you the
most would be like you know motivation
curiosity you know just you know stick
to it next how did I convey that to you
was it an example or did was it
something that I said with words because
when we when we hack together sometimes
you become unresponsive for like four
hours and that's like seriously um that
was like I think one of the most
important things to me W like of course
like no I mean don't get me wrong I I
think I learned a lot of tips like
really great things from you but for
example like those things if you push
hard you can kind of hard like find them
on Google sometimes right right for sure
but like in term I learn I learned them
from Google but in terms of like
curiosity or like this attitude of like
stick to your computer for 12 hours till
you find some vulnerabilities that's
like I think the biggest thing I learned
from you that yeah I think it's
different seeing somebody do it in
person too yeah you know that's one of
the things that I've done I've learned
from the live hacking events is like you
know at least for me I typically require
a um a pretty uninterrupted environment
to work in you know but you know when at
the live hacking event it could be a
little bit hard for me to focus or or
work with others right like I normally
try to get my headphones on I try to get
in the zone I wasn't really sure how to
like actually collaborate with other
hackers in an effective way but being at
the live hacking events and seeing
people collaborating together seeing
what worked with them it makes you
realize it's possible right um so it's
not always it's not always the technical
tips right it's not I guess is what
you're saying you know it's it's about
the work ethic and the and the drive as
well and I think you had that as well
and you you brought up a great point
about sort of knowing yourself um and
how you learn and how you work right and
at the end of the day pushing yourself
to find the vulnerability just through
grinding essentially right and it it
makes me think of one um of a quote that
I remember from you working together
which was you're looking at your screen
and you're getting kind of frustrated
you're like ah all right
I need some
carbohydrates that's what you said to me
and I was like dude that is not how I
think at all you know like like like I I
I um you know I'd be like oh man what
what like why can't I focus right now
like this is so annoying you know I get
frustrated at that but you know from
your own I guess from studying
experiences that that you're like ah you
know what this feeling I know this
feeling I've I've felt this feeling
before this is me needing to have
carbohydrates right right um so how do
you I mean is that something that just
kind of came natural to you or is that
something you had to start doing
cognizantly is starting to learn you
know yourself and how what makes you
study best and What Makes You focus
best super a hard question uh we don't
we don't we don't do easy questions here
on critical thinking my man so for one
carbohydrate thing sweet things that's
like pretty much like Japanese saying
you know am I
you know I need some sweet things oh
really to make my brain work so that's
the
one interesting yeah I wonder if it's a
I wonder if it's a cultural piece you
know like like I guess and I guess this
is I mean this is just scientifically
true right you know that carbohydrates
will help you focus in the short term
you know right or sugar sugary things
help you focus in the short term but
long term it's not not the best so if
you're at the end of your like you know
studying cycle or whatever and you're
really having trouble crossing the
finish line or finishing and then you
could hit some carbohydrates that's a
that's an interesting that's an
interesting little tidbit there maybe I
thought you were genius but maybe it's
just your Japanese maybe so yeah maybe
so solid man
um yeah so I think a lot of a lot of I
guess growing and hacking has to do with
that sort of learning yourself and uh
and that sort of thing any anything else
come to mind between the two of you
about uh
about I guess either learning
environment pluses or
um learning technique okay so let let me
ask you about this
okay when you work with a mentor one of
the reasons I I won't Mentor people is
because it takes a lot of time right and
I don't have time to Mentor everyone um
and this specific industry is not very
conducive to
mentorship because at the end of the day
if I teach you about idore
you didn't learn the skills necessary to
learn idore by yourself hopefully that
wasn't my phone
just but um you know you don't learn the
skills that you need to to learn idore
yourself you learned it from me so how
has it been transitioning from uh
mentorship in bug bounty to
self-education and let's start with Codi
on that one if you're if if that's not
too much on the spot because I know it's
a complicated question and it really it
really is yeah yeah
um H I think in that respect I'm still
in the process of you know really making
that transition in a way developing that
skill yeah really just you know having
more self-discipline to just you know
keep
um to really stick to my computer you
know for many hours um can you share any
tricks that you have cuz that's Journey
right that whole that whole experience
of developing that that skill is a
journey and I forget that journey I
don't really remember what it was like
to
not know how to take technical Concepts
and break it down and you know
assimilate it and bring it into my brain
you know um and especially coming from a
non-technical background like English
for you and French for so um I'm
wondering if there's any tips you can
share for the people that in a similar
spot and trying to develop that skill in
the first
place H and even things that haven't
worked you know like maybe I I tried
taking a break every 10 minutes you know
and then just discovered that that
didn't work you know and anything that
comes to mind on that on that
front it's a really good
question I think it's a really simple
thing and everyone says this but I guess
like you just have to find what you love
to do right like like for the first few
month uh when I just started to do B
bony and first few month where I started
to get some bounties as was like I was
telling to all my friends like you guys
all got to do this because you can make
money right but like from like a year
ago or two I started to realize that I
can do this because I love to do this
you know right it's not because uh
there's money
hanging there not not because of that I
just do this because I love to learn new
things and because I think hacking is
really cool and something that helps
others so that's
like so I don't like try to force myself
to study farther or like push
harder you know so so okay that's true
that's definitely true so focus on doing
the things you love the specific
vulnerability type that you love you
know maybe you should just dive deep
into that because you're fueled and it's
going to be so much easier the friction
is going to be less but we all get to
the point so where we've read the
JavaScript files 10 times and we need to
hack this Target and we can't hack it
and you're exhausted and you hate
it you know and I but okay okay but he
does actually have a little bit of weird
saying though that that Mariah my wife
always says about so he's like when when
somebody asks her how what kind of
person so is Mariah says he's the sort
of person that says the that says this
don't you just love that feeling when
your brain is so tired that you can't do
anymore end quote and and so I mean do
you have those moments or is it just of
course of course I have but and do you
push through or do you give up I give up
okay cuz uh I think that's one thing
that's different from you because I'm
not full-time B Bounty Hunter at the end
of the day I have a full-time job that
gives me monthly salary so I always
stick to what I kind of want or do so
these days I'm not necessarily doing
Black Books black Bounty whole time
trying to find CVS trying to you know
understand other pe people's fine right
stuff like that and whenever I feel like
I don't feel like you know going farther
on this path I just give up that's
that's that's really insightful and and
I think that can get you really far I
mean clearly that can get you really far
um and I think a lot of the bug Bounty
stuff that we talk about is a very grind
heavy mentality and I think if you are
to do bug Bounty fulltime you will run
into those sort of grind situations but
you also have to know when to set it
aside and say hey I'm actually not going
to grind anymore on this I've got you
know enough bugs in my pipeline that's
GNA pay my bills I don't need to sit
here and Shred my brain you know trying
to figure out some of this stuff that
that isn't you necessarily relevant to
uh or or is too much uh mental expend
too much mental cost right um for for
what it's worth and maybe move on to a
different Target or maybe pivot
around that being
said I made this mistake earlier on in
my career where I
would do manual testing but I would do
it wide and I would move very quickly
over the attack surface and this is
something that Douglas day and I um
Archangel sort of debated on a last
podcast was like how quickly do you move
on from a Target how quickly do you move
on from a section of the application and
I noted that when I started being more
stubborn about an attack Vector about a
bug I um I started finding better bugs
you know for the first like two years
maybe maybe not quite two years May
about two years of my bug Bounty journey
I never found a um a five-digit
vulnerability so vulnerability above
$10,000 um um and uh and then when I
started being a little bit more stubborn
I and a little bit more you know
mentally
resilient I uh I started finding more
bugs uh that of higher impact but I but
less bugs overall right which is a
definitely a mentality
shift um so yeah I'm sorry bringing it
back around could I um did you have any
thoughts
on what what what was my question now um
I guess did you have any qu do you have
any thoughts on what things have worked
for you and haven't worked for you
developing sort of the mental resilience
that's necessary or the ability to
intake new bug Bounty techniques things
that have worked or that haven't worked
and it's okay to say no we can move on
to the next question but um you know
it's very much a process along the way
and it might not be a process that
you're
undergoing cognizantly something that's
in the Forefront of your mind it could
rather be something that's in the back
of your mind
and something that you haven't really
thought through but but the whole you
know point of this is to try to bring
those things to the front of our minds
so that we can share with others how
they might have a
shortcut so do you have any thoughts on
that it's really just me being kind of
weird probably but uh I try
to because when you do some hacking you
could just be
basically sitting in the desk for many
hours just like that yeah so I try to
you know yeah one of the things that I
that I've been trying to do these days
is
just you know sit in front of my
computer
for about 50 minutes and
then you know have like a five minute
break to do some push-ups ah or you know
squats right and
then have to work I've seen you I've
seen you do that with your little timer
you'll set a timer and then you know
sometimes I guess sometimes it's a
stopwatch going up and then and do you
ever do a one going down or is it mostly
one going
down what do you mean stopwatch is I
mean like you press start and then it
starts counting one two three four five
and then versus a timer where a timer is
I do both oh do you really yeah so tell
me about what why do you why do you use
both
that's a really good question sometimes
I so one of the things I really it
because you're an absolute maniac and
just switch it up every time no you just
have a reason okay sometimes I kind of
want
to keep track of what I've been doing
and you know to sort of help myself do
that um
successfully I kind
of sometimes I just want to know how
much time exactly I spent on doing one
specific thing so yeah when I try to do
that it's definitely the time you know
uh going up okay
sure but as I said I do both so I
gota yeah in a way as I said I do both
I'm still doing it in a really frantic
manner
so is that okay so a little sporadic a
little bit Yeah okay gotcha um that that
makes sense I mean but but you found
that that technique helps you and then
when once you get up and you do the
push-ups and you return to your work
that is something that that sort of um
for me I think would cause some mental
friction and some context switch so your
brain says oh I'm working on something
else sorry I should bring the mic with
me um working on something else uh and
then going back to the thing you're
working on before it's a little bit of a
reset right and so I I try to avoid
those things but I know I acknowledge
that they're necessary um
how do you do you think that helps
increase your focus or do you think that
helps you your focus in the short term
or do you think that's more of a long
term like allows you to work more hours
because you have those breaks or
both honestly I've never really thought
of it from that perspective I just
thought hey I got to do something
healthy for my body but yeah definitely
I think I got to pay more attention to
that aspect as well so so for you this
is more of a counteracting the the
physical sitting in a chair staring at a
screen for a little while yeah pretty
much yeah that's very that's very
important um very good so that that's
some of the some of the I
guess things that have worked or things
that some
tips what kind of things do you have to
share that about my mentorship style in
particular or about your bug Bounty
Journey that haven't
worked um and I'll I'll I'll toss one up
there for you what kind of music do you
guys like to listen
to while you're do you listen to music
do you listen to sounds are there any
experiences that you've had that but not
Loop
yeah tell the people about that one so
so yeah so I think about this topic I
think I wanna talk about two things like
you know something that haven't worked
and the first one is kind of joke which
is about music is you know you because
you keep listening exact the same music
for like literally for like 12 hours and
then like keep singing the same phrase
for like six
hours and then on top of that you say
like this works so you got to do it and
it doesn't right so it just doesn't
work yeah yeah that is a little bit that
is I realize now that that may not be a
universal no principle so that yeah yeah
the the the thing you know that I that I
do the reason why I do that I've
explained it to you and I'll explain it
to the people as well just in case it it
resounds with anyone is
um I tend to get phrases or songs stuck
in my head I'm very susceptible to
earworms right um so when I have a song
in my head uh it will be taking up
mental space and so instead of having it
in my head I I opt to have it in my ears
on on repeat on Loop and what that does
is it takes it out of my head out of the
working space in my head and puts it in
in the ears and makes so I don't have to
think about it and then that frees up
that mental space right for me to
actually do things um but the result of
that is that I'm listening to the same
song on repeat for 12 hours sometimes
and sometimes singing the same thing on
repeat for 12 hours uh which can drive
your mes absolutely baddy absolutely
nuts um so that so I mean an alter
alternative to that for you is what what
works for
you or or did you have something else to
share on the things that don't work or
things that do work well yeah so the
second thing that I was gonna say the
second thing if this because this I
think podcast is for like maners ship
and stuff yeah I think this is a case
for like every mhip with a absolute
beginner and top guy okay is that like
so that like top hackers like you have
already forgot what it was like when you
were a beginner right so you forgot like
what was like common sense right and
what is like something you have to learn
right so you explain something without
realizing that you're like in Assumption
is not shared by menes right right so
that it's not just about you it kind of
happens with no no no say say say it
like it's about me though yeah so yeah
this is good practice for you providing
consis yeah like the reason why I'm not
pointing this to you is because it was
like the last session was like you know
year ago yeah so I don't like really
vividly remember what kind of things
that was I I remember you giving me this
feedback during our our training
sessions though too and I think that's
one of the things that I I'm glad you
mentioned this because that's one of the
things that I wanted to sort of bring up
in this and and I saw you nodding as
well Kodi and this is kind of one of the
things that I wanted to extract from you
to during this podcast is is my phone is
freaking out as much as you can remember
um what
is what are the things that are common
sense and are not common sense right uh
and and I know that that probably to
this you know right now not many things
are coming to mind um but in as much as
you
can I guess try to equ and it doesn't
even necessarily have to be specific
topics
but I guess even just equipping The
Listener with the ability to say hey
there's something that I'm missing here
like like what you just said right
there's some assumption that you are
making that I am not making and it's not
clicking right I think that's I think
that's really good as well so how do you
how do you identify those scenarios to
be honest I I think uh understanding on
anything is not like black and white
right you start from zero and trying to
shoot for 100 right so that I think
that's why it's really hard to identify
is
because so the first time you hear that
like your understanding of something is
like two right but the next time you
hear that your understanding is like 45
right so that's why you understand that
better
right but you don't necessarily identify
why it was there is difference sure and
you never understand something for like
100% I think it's always hard to say
like
what was something that I missed yeah
you know yeah no that that makes sense
could I do you have any any thoughts on
on any of that identifying areas that
may be common sense to Justin that are
preventing you from clicking or is it in
those scenarios do you often just find
yourself like man for whatever reason
this isn't clicking maybe it's the
common sense thing you
know yeah one of the things I really
struggle with I mean I still do in that
sense
is I think especially for beginners a
lot of
the you know behaviors of web browsers
in general maybe could be very
counterintuitive and because you're
already you know as a mentor and a you
know an Adept hacker guy you're just
know you have all the you know knowledge
and uh yeah so
it's like so browser internals maybe
like understanding exact like what kind
of uh limitations there are in the
browser and and maybe even what kind of
capabilities there are in the browser
yeah I remember one thing I remember one
thing all right C sorry save sorry you
need to go go to the file file save save
State you know okay say all right there
was one moment where I realized that
it's not just server side and client
side you know there's browser yeah
client side and server side right but if
you mix client and browser there's just
ton of thing you cannot understand
especially with like a you know cross
thing cross origin thing explain that a
little bit what what do you mean by
that like the client isn't necessarily a
browser is that what you're talking
about or or what so I don't I cannot
understand why I couldn't understand
because now I kind of understand it
right but there's server right there's
client site right and browser visits
this client site right so there are
three three parties okay so the
representation of yeah yeah yeah okay
wow that's interesting okay so that's a
really interesting representation of
that to me because I I do you know and
the the client side is I guess the
browser for me in some capacity but
really the way you've described it the
browser is the piece of software that is
quote unquote processing the client side
right is that is that how you're seeing
it I mean no necessarily but there's
just one moment that I was like oh
that's why there's this restriction that
has to be in place to protect you know
users okay because because it's I'm I'm
seeing I'm seeing that that's that's a
very interesting see right kind of hard
to like explain which part is important
to understand like what technology is
like it's really hard to explain but
just that whole concept and yeah the
browser being a piece of software itself
that has you know saved state right with
cookies and and then you know a
segmentation with different browser tabs
and different Origins and stuff like
that and not all of that is represented
in just the you know client side
response from from the server right the
because you could hit it with curl and
you'd get some data back right but the
browser is a much more complex mechanic
is that sort of what you're talking
about but at the same time yeah I agree
with that then same time Sam's browser
visits client side
like when you use Chrome instead of Carl
then then looks like they're just two
parties you know kind things and then it
it renders and and that's yeah and then
you just get confused right okay that
that that's an interesting that's an
interesting way of understanding it I I
I think you know if I try to force my
own understanding on you of that uh you
know it it could become confusing and
also like even even me right now I
couldn't I mean I cannot understand why
I couldn't understand that three years
ago so right if if you know three years
ago we came up here I I think I would do
the same thing as as Justin did like
three years ago like you know having
hard time
explaining like Common Sense sure sure
yeah so that's H yeah yeah that makes
sense so so bringing it back to Kodi
sorry thank you for interjecting there
so um so you were saying you know I
guess just making the mentee in the
situation aware of sort of how the
browser works and what kind of
restrictions are in the browser that's
where a lot of the assumptions are
coming in is that is that kind of what
you were
saying yeah kind of and it's just it's
not necessarily it's not just about you
know web browsers it could be just you
know just yeah anything like multiple
servers and stuff and yeah it's
so has been really easy for for me to
lose track of what was going on like you
know in the middle of listening to you
um your explanation basically right
right yeah oh like even when what
happened when right and do you think it
helped in particular when we used visual
representations like on a whiteboard
yeah yeah that was that was big for you
yeah that was a massive help okay
gotcha good look look at that guys some
good some good feedback don't listen to
uh to songs on Lop for 12 hours at least
not over you know speakers rather than
in
headphone and uh try to be aware of the
Common Sense bias right also like I
think I have another solution for me
that I found is so these days I work a
lot with Rota who you know obviously
another super good hackers so he does a
lot of things to me like where you know
there are like a lot of you know Common
Sense gaps and what I do all the time
and what he says to me all the time he's
like okay let's just stop this and you
know just you know put this aside for a
few months and then I come back to the
same same concept like three month later
to see if I understand that you know and
and that that that works yeah that works
we kind of we kind of give up
understanding that he kind of give up
teaching me that and I kind of give
understanding that to my thir I'm like
why I didn't understand that you know
that's another solution that is uh
that's so foreign to me yeah I would
never ever ever ever ever do that you
know like that and this is great because
that this a brilliant segue into the
next section that I wanted to say which
was like how has it has your you know
and also I'll let you I'll cue this up
and let you guys think about it for a
second how has working with other
hackers um influenced your hacking so
you know for you maybe that's so uh or
or any other hackers you've collaborated
with you know being near the live
hacking events or maybe it's just me you
know I don't know how much collaboration
you've done outside but so you've done
you know some other
collaborations how has that been and
what things have been different that
that you've learned now that crazy ass
thing you said a second ago about Yota
dude I can't I can't even process that
because
like for me if I let something like that
go all the all of the working memory you
know all of the data in Ram just just
drops right and and sure maybe I'm a
little bit more of a mature hacker you
know a couple months down the line but
man maybe it's just the stubbornness too
that I just don't want to let that thing
even temporarily defeat me I don't even
want to lose the battle even if it's
going to win me the war in the in the
long run and actually this this
correlates me this may just be my
personality too because uh I know you
guys know Mariah and and how Mariah and
I work but let's say Mari and I are
having an argument
right in the moment I'll be like we got
to fix this right now you know know and
and we just got to talk this through and
then we'll just be back to normal and
everything will be better right um but
for Mariah sometimes it it it say hey we
need to take even a five or 10 minute
break and just breathe and then just
come back to the situation right I see
that
where I can picture that yeah yeah where
whereas I I would never do anything like
that so uh it's good to see I mean so
that's great to hear that you found
other you know other mentors or other
you know hackers to collaborate with
that have also shared with you other
ways of of you know growing and finding
essentially uh a scenario where it's
like okay well hey you don't understand
that now and that's okay but let's come
back to this a little bit and maybe
putting a reminder on your calendar on
your to-do list or something say revisit
this topic yeah so okay hopefully you
haven't been too engaged with what I'm
saying and you've been thinking about
what what other hackers youve you've
worked with a little bit um Kai do you I
mean why don't you start because I'm not
I'm not sure do you have other hackers
that you've collaborated with obviously
so but besides
me um not really I
mean uh Som yeah that's true yeah and
other friend of ours he was actually on
probably the episode 10 of this podcast
yeah but uh yeah I I think only him
really outside of you know not outside
he's still inside of this Inner Circle
right right right right right yeah so we
we throw him he's in software it's a
little different you know something's a
little bit wrong with him um uh yeah so
okay you've worked a little bit with uh
with with Som um but besides that mostly
just me and so yeah yeah all right well
that'll be an interesting Journey for
you to see you know as you start
collaborating with other hackers so
you've worked pretty heavily with uh
with do um you've worked pretty heavily
with oota and and some other hackers as
well um oota and I are very different uh
anything any uh any sort of I
guess I almost want to say culture shock
but anything you know what what are some
things that have worked better with you
with
Yota or that have worked differently
with with Yota obviously you've got the
the Japanese piece
right yeah so is it like in terms of
mentorship or just in terms of like
generally in terms of General hacking or
mentorship and then also yeah maybe
maybe actually take a second to talk
about the bilingual piece of this as
well because you know we tried to do it
was actually a part of the way that I
picked up Japanese was trying to teach
you hacking in Japanese and you
correcting my Japanese and that sort of
thing but that's a very slow and painful
process to try to hear a non-native
speaker explains stuff and also there's
a lot of English terms right so um how
has it
worked with you being having a
conversation with OTA in your native
language uh and how has that helped you
understand things or get a better grip
on on stuff so uh for one one I guess uh
you know having um training with you in
English and Japanese I I didn't really
feel like language
barrier and like this is actually maybe
just about me but like for example if I
read some document in English and then
later visit the same thing translated in
Japanese especially with a like
technology thing it's easier to
understand in English because
everything's from the not always from
the states but everyone writes their
writs up in English ah so the original
is in English and that because of that
you get the Nuance better yeah so
there's some friction in terms of
language but if I read um translated
version I have a friction of translation
in my mind so M it's not necessarily a
huge
barrier yeah that makes sense and when
you've worked with uh Rota obviously
you're speaking Japanese with him um do
you think you've been able to understand
Concepts any better when to explain him
in Japanese or um I guess he explains
like super heart things
so yeah but like I really appreciate
that he speaks Japanese
h of course uh one because we can I can
understand I mean like I can get any
nuances better in
Japanese I don't know just in terms of
technology and techniques and stuff I
think it's not necessarily the case
maybe like if someone can speak Japanese
it's easier to you know get along with
their because it's hard it's hard facts
most of the time it's not like Nuance a
lot of times right you know so I I guess
that that sort of makesense as well and
and you guys are to the point you know
where you're fluent enough in English
obviously because we're doing this
podcast in English where you know most
of the hard facts most of the you know
pretty straightforward you know things
that don't have a lot of wiggle room uh
those those come come through pretty
well I'd imagine um any other any other
thoughts so on collaboration with other
hackers As you move sort of out of this
menty stage into full-fledged I mean I
guess like with Rota it's not really
like a collaboration it's kind of same
as you but like the big difference is I
think you're you can do both black box
and white box but I think you have more
experience on Black Box I think real
does the opposite he can do both but
he's strong is a white box so I whenever
I learn from from Rota I learned
something different from like what I
learned from you so yeah I think that's
another big difference I guess so how
did you establish that relationship with
udota where you were getting that
information back and forth in the
beginning was it you messaging him a lot
or did he sort of pursue you with I mean
it's always me messaging like spamming
rot on
disc all right so I think there's a
lesson there right what's that
lesson if you find some someone really
good at hacking just Spam
them Just
J nice nice okay Sol like seriously
there are many people like you know
really generous in this industry I'm I'm
I'm sure like I'm serious about that
like like you real Tech like I mean real
Tech get like zero Yen or zero doll
dollar if you prefer yeah but he still
answers a lot of questions so yeah yeah
that's really that that is cool and and
and I guess um you
know like you said spamming uh I think
spamming is not exactly what you're
doing right you're you're you normally
in my experience with you despite there
being a lot of messages those messages
are pointed and they are specific and
they are good questions essentially
right not not stuff that
you would be able to look up on Google
or things that you could ask you know
chat GPT or whatever right um and uh and
because of that I think I think that
makes it a lot easier for us to answer
you know those things so I think that's
good um all right let me see let me see
uh where we're at here uh we're doing
another mobile recording so it's a
little bit outside of the normal flow of
things all right we're at an hour 10 um
let's see if there's anything else that
uh we want to talk about here um yeah
so this last little sort of section is
kind of reigniting the the uh mentorship
of sorts okay and kind of talking about
where you guys let's talk honestly about
where you guys are at at in your uh
hacker journey and what kind of things
you would like to change or grow in okay
um so since you've got a little bit more
experience I'm GNA let you think on that
one a little bit Kodi um would you give
me a little bit of a summary on what
kind of things you're you're working on
or what kind of uh weaknesses that you'd
like to try to overcome right now sure
um so what I'm currently working on
is uh I
basically I'm in the process of trying
to have a more comprehensive
understanding of uh common vulnerability
types because I only know uh just
several V and access control pretty much
right yeah yeah yeah and uh yeah so I'm
working on that and because of you
know lack of knowledge I sometimes try
to do some BG Bounty but cannot really
go super deep like into one program so
in a way maybe
it's I feel like it's making it easier
for me to sort of almost move on because
hey there's not much I can do that I
understand yeah yeah so so you know
whenever that happens I try to you know
kind of rever back to port sger or
something and or you know just reading
some reports and like how hey this one
you know other vulnerability works like
recently I studied ssrf and stuff yeah
so starting to get a grip on those
slowly slowly but surely yeah and and
and so when you when you get into a
program and you start hacking and then
you're you know you're not finding
vulnerabilities could you describe the
feelings that are coming up and that and
like the is there frustration there is
there do you feel confident in your
direction that you're going you know how
how is
that I know I will say I'm asking you
guys to be pretty vulnerable here
because there are a lot of people that
from our side as the hacker SES
genuinely want to help you know people
to grow right and there are a lot of
people in your shoes that genuinely want
to grow and they want to overcome these
sort of feelings that they're having and
I think knowing that there are other
people experiencing those things and
overcoming them as you guys are I think
that helps so I'm sorry for putting you
on the spot with some difficult
questions about yourself and your
current Journey but I think it's it'll
be
helpful yeah
um sorry
uh I haven't really in a pragmatic sense
implemented this method yet but um yeah
the feeling of hey maybe there's not
much I can do that I
understand that definitely makes me um
you know frustrated and lost to a
degree
but sorry what was a question again yeah
yeah no no I guess so that that that
makes sense you know lost to a degree
right and and and so I guess what what
are what are some other things that are
sort of coming up as you're as you're
going through that and how does that
affect your journey like do you leave
the computer frustrated or and how do
you sort of process that uh what kind of
stuff's coming
up I do leave my computer kind of
frustrated yeah um but
I I'm aware that there's a need for me
to you know in that sort of situation at
least lay out you know all the things
that I've already tried good and and
then move on or still you know stick to
what I was working on yeah how much time
are you spending on a Target before you
move along to go back to
education another great question
um just a ballpark's fine you know I I
realize you're probably not recording
this you know did four hours on this
Target today or whatever
no probably should yeah I think that'd
be helpful
yeah
I don't know it could be sometimes super
I guess unnecessarily long sometimes
yeah just for almost a week yeah so like
roughly 40 hours or roughly 30 hours in
a week yeah like roughly
yeah 30 to 35 hours a week like although
I don't really have you know I don't
even understand many types of
vulnerabilities and and we've kind of
talked about this as well is like you
know you're going in there you're
spending time in the requests reading
the request right trying to understand
what's happening and you know maybe
you'll leave that situation frustrated
that maybe you haven't found a v but
every single time you read a request and
you try to understand what's going on
you're gaining reps you know you're
you're it's like you know it's like
you're doing the workout you know and
you're you're becoming stronger at
analyzing requests understanding what's
happening and reducing that friction to
the next time you try and attack Vector
um so yeah I think I think 40 hours um
on a Target
uh you know I think like you said that
that's probably or or 30 30 to 35 is
what you said
um probably probably it's had bit long
without without you know having more
direction or more it's probably about
right you know about but maybe on the
long side if you've only got two two
vulnerability types right I mean would
you you're making some uh sort of
agreement sound so do you do you agree
with that or do you disagree with that
like do you think that's long for him to
be on a Target at this point in his in
his journey I mean I actually was
thinking from pretty different
perspective which is that so I think
like the biggest difference uh between
you and us is like we really lack a lot
of
Basics so sometimes I feel like the
reason why I don't find that the the
same amount of access control box like
even in idors as you it's not because I
don't have enough reps but also because
you have generally better understandings
on like different things and I don't
know how they're all connected
but the kind of same argument as you
know better haaka knows like how to how
to c stuff
so and so I guess that basic knowledge
are are you saying that that's something
more like so I'm able to extract more
attack surface out of the
the the program or out of the
application or do you think that's
actually like you know basic knowledge
as in like for
example um because at the end of the day
idors are idors you sub the IDS you you
know you figure it out we all know how
that works right you know the reason
you're not finding the idors is there's
two reasons one you didn't try the
request two you didn't find the request
but for example if you take a Jason for
example yeah um the first few month I
didn't know that swapping you know key
value stuff really make most of the time
no difference sometimes of course right
but if you have like completely
different Keys yeah and then swapping
them doesn't really affect anything sure
but you didn't know that so I think I
would I had tried you know swapping them
at least once but it's a waste of time
swapping swapping meaning what like
changing the order Keys okay yeah yeah
very limited scenarios where that that
you know has some imp it's like a test
you know back slash and maybe that works
but test one test two I don't know right
right kind of so then I waste time there
the same like for cash Behavior
sometimes you say like this is dead end
but I just you know keep pushing forward
for like another hour to realize that
this is this is actually dead end sure
so then I kind of start to think like
maybe I have to increase like General
understanding of cyber security computer
science so yeah I think that that's what
I think I like how so many of your
examples are about Json pollution right
now because you read that article
recently you're like
oh also because uh you you brought up
Json as the the first thing I learned
right right ever since that day he's
been obsessed with
Json um yeah that that makes sense
um having some things that you don't
that you you've got to kind of figure
out for yourself are dead ends you know
and also testing the assumptions we talk
about this a lot on the podcast but
everyone has their own set of eyes right
and I can tell you so that that's a dead
end but until you've gone down that path
it's hard for you to know that that's a
dead end and that's the hacker mentality
right because every time you you try to
you know go to SL admin you're going to
get 403 right
but you can't trust that 403 you know
and you got to try admin slash you got
to try admin perc OA slash you know you
know that too if you know what is like
you know what backend is like if you
have ever seen like engine next
configuration once right you might think
about that but if you have never seen
that a point it's just a waste of time
yeah because you don't know how things
could get wrong go wrong so so I guess
the thing that I was I was so so I guess
bringing that back around to Codi
situation you know spending 30 hours or
35 hours you know with two two
vulnerability types I think there's sort
of a blog post that I'm working on with
essentially a a percentages scenar you
know layout where I say okay you know
after you
know
idor Access Control bugs SS xss curf um
and then you know maybe a couple other
things you should be spending 60% of
your time hacking and 40% of your time
learning right because those bugs make
up their majority of you know the bugs
that are found right um but you know
Kodi is not quite at that spot yet so I
think Kodi you might still be at like an
8020 right where in a week you're
spending you know 80% of your time
learning and then 20% of your time
actually hacking and as that continues
to grow you know as you you you know
your your vulnerabilities that you're
comfortable with continue to grow that's
when you sort of increase the the
attacking uh the actual hacking piece
the hands on the keyboard piece does
that make sense does that ReSound with
you yeah it does no you should grab the
mic for that we only got one mic sorry
about that does that ReSound with you it
does yeah yeah
um I think that might help reduce
frustration and help increase you know U
feeling of of progress in in bug Bounty
yeah um what kind of vulnerabilities
right now you mentioned ssrf uh has that
been your primary focus for the past
couple weeks or there other
vulnerability types you're learning
about um xxe injections oh nice yeah and
I also try to look for some csfs as well
ah nice yeah yeah we did cover that a
little bit together and a bit of exis
very nice yeah um good stuff dude yeah I
guess that's about it nice keep at it
for those of you listening I just gave
Kodi a little little fist bump and it
kind of kind of hurt the knuckles all
right all right so so so talk to me a
little bit about where you're at in your
journey what kind of things you're
trying to improve on and what kind of
stuff you're trying to um uh yeah grow
in what's working what's not working for
you right now I guess I'm like these
days like 90% learning 10% hacking yeah
yeah besides your job of course yeah of
course the reason for that is because so
like like 6040 ratio yeah I think that
really works if you want to become a
good back bu H Hunter as fast as
possible but now my goal is just you
know have fun learning new things and
trying to like put that into practice
like try to apply exploits that I found
in a wild stuff like that so I do more
of like reading blog post like you know
reading uh Twitter Twitter fees and also
like reading CVS try to find
CVS and sometimes do back Bounty and
then try to apply all these things that
I learned in like uh in the last two
weeks or three yeah into practice that's
like yeah what I do that's pretty solid
let's let's uh let's call some shots
here where do you want to be in uh in
two years where do you want to be in two
years careerly and where do you want to
be um you know I guess from a technical
perspective what things do you want to
understand what kind of bugs do you want
to be finding you know kind of research
do you want to be doing similar things
or yeah I'm thinking yeah show the shirt
he's wearing a shirt right now that says
thinking and then has a loading bar
that's halfway halfway done that's great
it's really hard so one there a lot of
things that I learn there a lot of blog
posts published like every day so like
on a daily basis I don't really have
like specific direction to go I just
have a lot of things that I learn that I
love to learn so I just do it and just
really vaguely I think it' be really
cool if I can do something like what
people in asset notes do like their blog
posts are like just crazy yeah we all we
all right we would all love to do that
yeah so like at at some point it would
be really cool if I can do kind of same
thing which is you know Finding like
crazy exploit on like big yeah vendor so
semi sort of semi white box
security research right but yeah black
Bo is cool too so yeah yeah yeah and and
what asot doesn't does is not
necessarily white box but they try as
best they can to make it white box right
they try to as much they can to get
their Hands-On source code and do
reverse engineering um uh and sometimes
they they have to deal with the binary
exploitation stuff and sometimes they
get their hands on yeah so that's white
box so I think in terms of black box
like something like I I I can't just
pronounce his name but Yu samura yeah
the Facebook guy yeah if I can just all
I his stuff is is largely white box too
because it's front end and you have
front-end code yeah so I think that's
maybe like
something at least a bit of source Cod
the thing is what I want to do I guess
that's cool yeah so you you kind of want
to go down the source code reading and
then vulnerability finding rout yeah
nice CI uh I think your goals are a
little different you know you mentioned
before being able to live a nomadic life
right you want to be a travel around and
work on your schedule what kind of goals
do you have for the future in in bug
Bounty so as I said at the beginning of
this podcast I'm in the process of you
know applying for some actual companies
right now so I just can't say hey I'm
only you know just focusing on doing
some bu bunny right right of course of
course and as much as I would I would I
tell you all the time man bug Bown is
the life you know I totally understand
that and and um you know some jobs allow
to work remote and some jobs don't allow
to work remote and I think it's
important for you to get in there and
you know have some career experiences as
well yeah yeah so it doesn't have to be
limited let's just make this more
broadly let's make it careerly yeah so
it's like you know that being said I do
still want to have the
capability of you
know I'm working and living
pneumatically like regardless of my
decisions uh so yeah um
so in two let me make this question a
little bit more specific in two to five
years what where would you like to see
yourself if one of the companies that
I'm applying for right now
yeah
really if one of them really like
clicked then I might just you know
naturally stick to yeah to it
but if that wasn't the cas
case I think I'd have tried to
spend more time
um in Buck Bounty and of course if that
didn't really work temporarily then I
tried to you know do more um studying
learning just like you know s does
and yeah yeah that makes sense do you do
you see bug Bounty more as a stepping
stone for you like a as a as a as a
stare to get to a destination you know
or do you see bug Bounty as something
that might stay in your life more long
term after you get a
job I want it to stay in stayed in my
life um
because all the book bounty hunters that
I've seen they're so they're all super
cool including you guys yeah and uh yeah
you just you know I just wanted there
something really badass yeah in my life
so yeah yeah did you say you you do or
you don't want want it to stay in your
life uh I would you do okay sorry c i i
i i misheard you there sorry about that
uh but uh uh sorry my poor articulation
no no you're good we always try to we
always troll K because he he spends so
much time you know really articulating
and speaking really well in English so
anytime I miss anything I have to give
him
a look gotcha
um so what about you we'll close with
this one but like what do you think you
see yourself staying in bug Bounty or do
do you think bug Bounty is a training
thing for you I mean I think i' love to
stay in B bu Bounty and that's just
simply because the the very first reason
I ditched like being Diplomat course
right right is because I thought it's
super cool to you know be like you be
like you know top hacker you know
Finding crazy
vulnerabilities and prot texting the
world that that sounds really cool so I
think that's the first inspir
inspiration so I think that's going to
stick to my mind I mean for a long term
I guess good good [__] guys all right
let's do it let's rock it let's find
those uh let's find those
vs so um as we finish off this episode
Ci's got a little bit of a of a uh of a
of a word of advice for an admonition
for those of you listening on on YouTube
what what what is that c i what have you
always wanted to say to the viewers yeah
just you know thank you all for watching
this uh listening to this podcast and
just definitely smash the description
and leave some likes in the comment
section smash description crucial it's
crucial that's crucial right there